Once upon a time
很久很久以前...
in a kingdom far, far away,
在一个远的要命的王国
the king and queen were blessed with a beautiful baby girl.
国王与王后生了一个美丽的公主
And throughout the land, everyone was happy...
王国里的每一个人都非常开心
until the sun went down
但是到太阳下山以后...
and they saw that their daughter was cursed with a frightful enchantment
国王与王后才发现... 公主被恐怖的咒语所诅咒
that took hold each and every night.
每天一到晚上咒语就开始生效
Desperate, they sought the help of a fairy godmother
于是心急如焚的 国王和王后向神仙教母救助
who had them lock the young princess away in a tower,
神仙教母要他们 把公主锁在高塔上
there to await the kiss...
等待超酷的白马王子前来吻她...
of the handsome Prince Charming.
破除咒语
It was he who would chance the perilous journey
白马王子经历千辛万苦
through blistering cold and scorching desert
走过夜晚冷得要死 白天热得要命的沙漠
traveling for many days and nights,
花上了好几天好几夜
risking life and limb
冒着生命的危险...
to reach the Dragon 's keep.
终于...  到了恶龙守护的高塔
For he was the bravest,
全天下...
and most handsome...in all the land.
最勇敢...最英俊的王子
And it was destiny
在命运的安排下
that
他知道...
his kiss
他香吻...
would break the dreaded curse.
将破除可怕的咒语
He alone would
王子...
climb to the highest room of the tallest tower to enter the princess's chambers,
爬上高塔顶端的公主房间
cross the room to her sleeping silhouette,
寻找房间内...美丽的睡美人
pull back the gossamer curtains to find her...
他拉开薄薄的纱想要亲吻公主...
What?
搞事啊?
Princess... Fiona?
你就是... 公主?
No!
不是!
Oh, thank heavens.
噢...差点被狼吻了
Where is she?
公主呢?
She's on her honeymoon
去度蜜月了
Honeymoon? With whom?
度蜜月...跟谁啊?
∮ So she said what's the problem, baby? ∮
∮ 她说 到底怎么回事 宝贝? ∮
∮ What's the problem? I don't know ∮
∮ 怎么回事?我哪里会知道 ∮
∮ Well maybe I'm in love ∮
∮ 或许是我恋爱了吧 ∮
《怪物史瑞克2》
∮ How much longer will it take to cure this? ∮
∮ 要多久我才能痊愈? ∮
∮ Just to cure it, 'cause I can't ignore it ∮
∮ 治愈 因为我无法坐视不管 ∮
∮ if it's love ∮
∮ 如果是爱  是爱情 ∮
∮ Makes me wanna turn around and face me ∮
∮ 令我想回头看看自己 ∮
∮ But I don't know nothing 'bout love ∮
∮ 可是我对爱情一窍不通 ∮
∮ Oh, come on, come on ∮
∮ 来吧 来吧 ∮
∮ Turn a little faster ∮
∮ 快一点 ∮
∮ Come on, come on ∮
∮ 来吧 来吧 ∮
∮ The world will follow after ∮
∮ 世界将跟随着你 ∮
∮ Come on, come on ∮
∮ 来吧 来吧 ∮
∮ Everybody's after love ∮
∮ 人人都在追求爱情 ∮
∮ So I said I'm a snowball running ∮
∮ 所以我说我是一个滚动的雪球 ∮
∮ Running down into this spring that's coming all this love ∮
∮ 滚进洋溢爱情的春天 ∮
∮ Melting under blue skies ,Belting out sunlight ∮
∮ 融入蓝天 迎接旭日 ∮
∮ Shimmering love ∮
∮ 光辉闪亮的爱情 ∮
∮ Well, baby, I surrender ∮
∮ 宝贝 我投降 ∮
∮ To the strawberry ice cream ∮
∮ 即使化作草莓冰淇淋 ∮
∮ Never ever end of all this love ∮
∮ 这份爱永不止歇 ∮
∮ Well, I didn't mean to do it ∮
∮ 这并不是甜言蜜语 ∮
∮ But there's no escaping your love ∮
∮ 但我将永不逃离你的爱 ∮
∮ These lines of lightning mean we're never alone ∮
∮ 这些光芒预示着我们将不再孤独 ∮
∮ Never alone, no, no ∮
∮ 永不孤寂  永不  永不 ∮
∮ Come on, come on ∮
∮ 来吧  来吧 ∮
∮ Jump a little higher ∮
∮ 再跳高一点 ∮
∮ Come on, come on ∮
∮ 来吧 来吧 ∮
∮ If you feel a little lighter ∮
∮ 假如你觉得轻松 ∮
∮ Come on, come on ∮
∮ 来吧 来吧 ∮
∮ We were once upon a time in love ∮
∮ 我们曾经相爱 ∮
∮ We 're accidentally in love ∮
∮ 我们意外地陷入情网 ∮
∮ Accidentally in love ∮
∮ 意外地陷入情网 ∮
∮ 意外的相爱 ∮
∮ Accidentally in love ∮
∮ 意外地陷入情网 ∮
∮ Accidentally ∮
∮ 意外 ∮
∮ I'm in love, I'm in love ∮
∮ 恋爱了 恋爱了 ∮
∮ Accidentally ∮
∮ 意外的相爱 ∮
∮ I'm in love ∮
∮ 恋爱了 ∮
∮ 我在恋爱 ∮
It's so good to be home!
回到家里的感觉真好!
Just you and me and...
终于剩下你跟我...还有...
∮ Two can be as bad as one... ∮
∮ 走一起不一定会更好... ∮
Donkey?
驴子?
Shrek! Fiona!
史瑞克! 费欧娜!
Aren't you two a sight for sore eyes!
看到你们好开心哦!
Give us a hug, Shrek,
过来抱抱好吗   史瑞克?
you old love machine.
你这可爱的小妖怪
And look at you, Mrs. Shrek.
哈哈哈... 还有你  史太太
How 'bout a side of sugar for the steed?
要不要给我来个亲亲呢?
Donkey, what are you doing here?
驴子  你在这里干什么?
Taking care of your love nest for you.
我来帮你照顾爱的小窝
Oh, you mean like... sorting the mail
喔  你是说... 你来帮我整理信件
and watering the plants?
还有浇花吗?
Yeah, and feeding the fish!
对呀 还有帮你喂金鱼!
I don't have any fish.
我根本没有养鱼
You do now.
现在养啊
I call that one Shrek and the other Fiona.
这只叫史瑞克 这只叫费欧娜
That Shrek is a rascally devil. Get your...
只是史瑞克最调皮了  不乖就打屁屁...
Look at the time. I guess you'd better be going.
噢...  你看现在很晚了耶 你该回去了
Don't you want to tell me about your trip?
耶...  蜜月旅行有什么好玩的?
Or how about a game of Parcheesi?
我们来玩骑马打仗...
Actually, Donkey? Shouldn't you be getting home to Dragon?
对了  驴子  你不是应该回家陪小龙女吗?
Oh, yeah, that.
哦...对哦
I don't know. She's been all moody and stuff lately.
她最近的情绪好像不太稳定
I thought I'd move in with you.
所以我还是搬来 跟你们一起住好了
You know we're always happy to see you, Donkey.
你也知道我们一直 都很欢迎你啊
But Fiona and I are married now.
可是费欧娜跟我已经结婚了
We need a little time, you know, to be together.
我们需要一点时间 可以彼此在一起
Just with each other.
在一起
Alone.
单独
Say no more. Say no more.
别再说了 别再说了
You don't have to worry about a thing.
你们不用担心   我会尽忠职守
I will always be here to make sure nobody bothers you.
不会让任何人来打扰你们的
Donkey!
驴子!
Yes, roomie?
什么事?
You're bothering me.
就是你打扰我们
Oh, OK. All right,
好吧...  我走就是了...
cool. I guess...  Me and Pinocchio was going to catch a tournament, anyway, so...
你真酷  此处不留爷   自有留爷处
Maybe I'll see y'all Sunday for a barbecue or something.
每天吃香的喝辣的...  没有什么了不起...
He'll be fine. Now,
他不会有事的 对了...
where were we?
我们刚刚到哪了?
I think I remember.
噢! 我想起来了...
Donkey!
驴子!!!
I know, I know! Alone! I'm going! I'm going.
我了!你们要在一起的 我不打扰你们
What do you want me to tell these other guys?
可是外面那些人没人理啊?
Enough, Reggie.
好了  别吹了
"Dearest Princess Fiona.
亲爱的费欧娜公主
"You are hereby summoned to the Kingdom of Far, Far Away
奉天承运  远的要命王国国王召曰
"for a royal ball in celebration of your marriage
你将奉旨出席皇室舞会 以庆祝你的婚礼
"at which time the King will bestow his royal blessing...
届时 国王将会在 舞会中赐福祝福你
" upon you and your...uh... Prince Charming."
跟你的...呃... 白马王子
"Love, the King and Queen of Far, Far Away.
爱你的远的要命 王国国王与王后
"aka Mom and Dad."
也就是你的父王母后
Mom and Dad?
父王跟母后?
Prince Charming?
白马王子?
Royal ball? Can I come?
皇室舞会...我也要去!
We're not going.
我们才不去呢
What?
什么!
I mean,
你不觉得...
don't you think they might be a bit... shocked
他们看到你的时候会... 吓一跳
to see you like this?
你看看你现在的样子...
Well, they might be a bit surprised.
也许他们是会吓一跳
But they're my parents, Shrek. They love me.
但是他们必竟是我的父母 他们爱我
And don't worry. They'll love you, too.
不要担心 他们也会爱你的
Yeah, right.
是哦 等哪天我是彭永俊 你不是如花再说吧
Stop it. They're not like that.
他们才不会以貌取人呢
How do you explain Sergeant Pompous
那为什么他刚才介绍我的时候
and the Fancy Pants Club Band?
语气那么不屑啊?
Oh, come on! You could at least give them a chance.
拜托... 你不试试看怎么会知道呢?
To do what? Sharpen their pitchforks?
是什么? 看会不会被丢石头?
No! They just want to give you their blessing.
不是  他们只是想要祝福你
Oh, great. Now I need their blessing?
搞什么  我干嘛需要他们的祝福啊?
If you want to be a part of this family, yes!
如果你想成为我的家人   就需要!
Who says I want to be part of this family?
谁说我想成为你们家人了?
You did! When you married me!
你呀? 你娶了我就是啦!
Well, there's some fine print for you!
好啊  原来你早有预谋
So that's it. You won't come?
不跟你说了   你去不去?
Trust me. It's a bad idea.
相信我  不会有搞头的了
We are not going! And that's final!
我们绝对不去   也不要再说了!
Come on! We don't want to hit traffic!
快点了  史瑞克. 不然会塞车哦!
Don't worry! We'll take care of everything.
放心  这里交给我们没有问题!
Hey, wait for me. Oof!
准备好了  来走...
Hit it! Move 'em on! Head 'em up! Head 'em up, move 'em on! Head 'em up!
来走了...来走来走   把头抬高!一下大叫
Rawhide! Move 'em on! Head 'em up!
把烦恼忘掉   又跟我一起唱一起跳
Move 'em on! Move 'em on! Head 'em up! Rawhide!
一起听笑   一起大叫...
(远的要命王国  700英里)
Are we there yet?
我们到了没?
No.
还没
Are we there yet?
我们到了没?
Not yet.
还没
(远的要命王国  200英里)
OK, are we there yet?
嘿...我们到了没?
No.
还...没
Are we there yet?
我们到了没?
No!
还没!
Are we there yet?
我们...到了没?
Yes.
到了
Really?
真的?
No!
假的!
Are we there yet?
我们到了没?
No!
还没!!!
Are we there yet?
我们到了没?
We are not!
我们还没到!
-  Are we there yet? - No!
- 我们到了没? - 还没...
Are we there yet?
我们到了没?
That's not funny.
一点都不好玩
That's really immature.
你这样很嫩耶
- This is why nobody likes you. - This is why nobody likes ogres.
- 就因为这样大家不喜欢你 - 就因为这样大家不喜欢驴子
Your loss!
好啦 算你赢了
I'm gonna just stop talking.
我不要跟你说话了
Finally!
太好了!
This is taking forever, Shrek.
还要走多久啊  什么烂车嘛
There's no in-flight movie or nothing!
应该装部卡拉OK
The Kingdom of Far, Far Away, Donkey.
我们要去的是... 远得要命王国
That's where we're going. Far, far...away!
远得要命王国  还真是...远得...要命啊
All right, all right, I get it
好啦  我了啦
I'm just so darn bored.
可是真的很无聊嘛
Well, find a way to entertain yourself.
无聊... 那就自己去找乐子
For five minutes...
5分钟就好
Could you not be yourself...
你就不能闭上你的驴嘴?
for five minutes!
只要5分钟就好!!!
Are we there yet?
哦...我们到了没?
Yes!
到了
Oh, finally!
终于到了!
(欢迎莅临 远的要命王国)
It's going to be champagne wishes
接下来我们每天都要吃好东西
and caviar dreams from now on.
鱼肉酒  吃到饱!
Hey, good-looking! We'll be back to pick you up later!
嘿  辣妹! 等一下我回来接你们哦!
(神仙教母   让你幸福快乐!)
It's too late to regret this time
这一次想后悔也来不及了
∮ Well  I talk about it... talk about it... ∮
∮ 好吧 我们谈谈吧 谈谈吧... ∮
Hey, everyone, look.
有一只驴子耶...
∮ Talk about it  talk about movin... ∮
∮ 说吧 说吧 ∮
Hey, ladies! Nice day for a parade, huh?
嗨  妹妹  帅哦!
You working that hat.
你戴那顶帽子 很像单留美耶!
Swimming pools! Movie stars!
灰姑娘? 游泳池耶! 电影明星!
Announcing the long-awaited return of the beautiful Princess Fiona
我们全国期待已久   美丽的费欧娜公主
and her new husband.
还有她的新婚夫婿驾到...
Well, this is it.
我们终于到了
This is it.
终于到了.
终于到了..
This is it.
终于到了...
Uh... why don't you guys go ahead? I'll park the car.
呃...你们先过去好了... 我去泊车
So...
怎样...
you still think this was a good idea?
妳还觉得来这里是对的吗?
Of course!
当然啦...
Look. Mom and Dad look happy to see us.
你看...父王跟母后 看到我们都很开心的
Who on earth are they?
那个丑女人是谁啊?
I think that's our little girl.
我想应该是我们的女儿吧?
That's not little! That's a really big problem.
这是我们的小乖乖吗? 怎么变成丑八怪了?
Wasn't she supposed to kiss Prince Charming and break the spell?
她不是应该被白马王子亲吻  破除咒语变漂亮了吗?
Well, he's no Prince Charming, but they do look...
问题是他不像白马王子  可是他们看起来...
Happy now?
开心啰?
We came. We saw them.
我们来了  也看到了他们了...
Now let's go before they light the torches.
还是趁他们没有抓狂前 赶快落跑吧
They're my parents.
他们是我父母耶
Hello? They locked you in a tower.
拜托  他们把你锁在高塔上耶
That was for my own...
那也是为了我...
Good! Here's our chance.
好!快点进去
Let's go back inside and pretend we're not home.
赶快躲到里面  假装不在家
Harold, we have to be...
哈洛  我们应该...
Quick! While they're not looking we can make a run for it.
快点  趁他们还没看清楚   赶快落跑...
Shrek, stop it! Everything's gonna be...
史瑞克!不要这样! 我们一定会...
A disaster! There is no way...
好惨啊  我就不相信...
You can do this.
你会做到的
I really... Really...
可是我真的... 真的...
don't...
不
want...
想..
to... be...
来...
Here!
到这里!
Mom...
母后!
Dad...
父王!
I'd like you to meet my husband...Shrek.
我跟你们介绍我老公 ...史瑞克
It's easy to see where Fiona gets her good looks from.
一看就知道费欧娜 这么漂亮是遗传谁的了...
Excuse me.
不好意思...
Better out than in, I always say, eh, Fiona? That's good.
打嗝总比放屁好   对不对 费欧娜?
I guess not.
大概不对吧
What do you mean, "not on the list"?
怎么名单上没有我?
Don't tell me you don't know who I am.
连我是谁都不知道...
What's happening, everybody? Thanks for waiting.
嘿...大家好啊... 差点迟到了
I had the hardest time finding this place.
这里真的很难找耶...
No! No! Bad donkey! Bad! Down!
不行不行  臭驴子  下去! 快下去!
No, Dad! It's all right. It's all right. He's with us.
不不  父王  没关系 没关系 他是我朋友
He helped rescue me from the dragon.
他也有帮我对付那只喷火龙
That's me: the noble steed.
嘿...就是我  高贵的"神驹"
Waiter! How 'bout a bowl for the steed?
喂  小二  帮我拿菜单来...
Oh, boy.
哦  天啊...
Um, Shrek?
呃...史瑞克...
Yeah?Oh, sorry!
干嘛? 哦 抱歉...
Great soup, Mrs Q.
汤很好喝  母后大人...
No, no. Darling.
不对 不对  是这样...
So, Fiona, tell us about where you live.
告诉我  费欧娜 你现在都住那里啊?
Well...Shrek owns his own land.
这个... 史瑞克有自己的土地
Don't you, honey?
对不对  老公?
Oh, yes!
噢  对呀!
It's in an enchanted forest
就在一个美丽的森林里面...
abundant in squirrels and cute little duckies and...
里面有很多的松鼠 还有天鹅...还有...
What?
什么? 哈哈哈...
I know you ain't talking about the swamp.
你是在说你那个沼泽啊?
Donkey!
驴子
An ogre from a swamp. Oh! How original.
一个住在沼泽的妖怪  喔  多传奇啊...
I suppose that would be a fine place to raise the children.
那里的环境... 应该蛮适合多养几个孩子的哦
It's a bit early to be thinking about that, isn't it?
现在说这些还太早了  对吧?
-  lndeed. I just started eating. - Harold!
-  没错! 我才要开始吃东西了呢! - 哈咯!
What's that supposed to mean?
你说这话是什么意思?
Dad.
父王!
It's great, OK?
他是好人!
For his type, yes.
我看他是个好妖怪!
My type?
好妖怪?
I got to go to the bathroom.
我...要去尿尿了...
Dinner is served!
主菜上桌了..
Never mind. I can hold it.
不要紧  我可以憋一下
Bon appetit!
用餐愉快!
Oh, Mexican food! My favorite.
噢 墨西哥菜! 我的最爱!
Let's not sit here with our tummies rumbling. Everybody dig in.
好啦  我们大家不要光顾 在这里抬杆  大家开动吧
Don't mind if I do, Lillian.
那我就不客气啰...
I suppose any grandchildren I could expect from you would be...
那我们将来你们给我生个孙子  应该会是个...
Ogres, yes!
妖怪...没错!
Not that there's anything wrong with that.
事情没那么严重嘛
Right, Harold?
对吧  哈洛?
Oh, no! No! Of course, not!
对对对  当然了
That is, assuming you don't eat your own young!
除非他能够证明他不会吃小孩
Dad!
父王!
No, we usually prefer the ones who've been locked away in a tower!
不对  我们对小孩承诺的方式 就是把他锁在高塔...
Shrek, please!
史瑞克  拜托!
I only did that because I love her.
我那么做是因为我爱她
Aye, day care or dragon-guarded castle.
是啊  爱到还找喷火龙来当保姆!
You wouldn't understand. You're not her father!
你根本不懂.你又不是她父亲!
It's so nice to have the family together for dinner.
一家人在一起 吃顿团圆饭还真好
-  Harold! - Shrek!
- 哈洛! - 史瑞克!
-  Fiona! - Fiona!
- 费欧娜 - 费欧娜
-  Mom! - Harold...
- 母后! - 哈洛!
Donkey!
驴子!
∮ Yourfallen tears have called to me ∮
∮ 你悲伤的眼泪告诉我 ∮
∮ So, here comes my sweet remedy ∮
∮ 有我拯救受伤的心 ∮
∮ I know what every princess needs ∮
∮ 我知道每位公主都 ∮
∮ For her to live life happily... ∮
∮ 想过得非常快乐地... ∮
Oh, my dear.
喔...天那...
Oh, look at you.
让我看看你
You're all
你长得...
grown up.
...好大了
Who are you?
呃...你是谁?
Oh, sweet pea! I'm your fairy godmother.
亲爱的  我是你的神仙教母啊
I have a fairy godmother?
我有神仙教母?
Shush, shush.Now, don't worry. I'm here to make it all better.
嘘...好了  不要担心 我是来帮助你的
With just a...
轻...轻...的...
∮ Wave of my magic wand Your troubles will soon be gone ∮
∮ 挥动我的魔仗 你烦恼雨消云散 ∮
∮ With a flick of the wrist and just a flash You'll land a prince with a ton of cash ∮
∮ 挥挥手  深处光芒就会有... ∮
∮ A high-priced dress made by mice no less ∮
∮ 多情的王子随你换 ∮
∮ Some crystal glass pumps And no more stress ∮
∮ 老鼠做起了高级洋装 ∮
∮ Your worries will vanish, your soul will cleanse ∮
∮ 和那富贵雕的玻璃鞋 ∮
∮ Confide in your very own furniture friends ∮
∮ 流行服装游荡在你的腰 ∮
∮ We 'll help you set a new fashion trend ∮
∮ 再帮你搞定所有流行资信 ∮
∮ I'll make you fancy ∮
∮ 会让你穿最流行服装 ∮
∮ I'll make you great ∮
∮ 我让你流行我让你炫! ∮
∮ The kind of girl a prince would date ∮
∮ 是王子最爱的女性 ∮
∮ They'll write your name on the bathroom wall... ∮
∮ 他们会对你找藉口 ∮
∮ For a happy ever after, give Fiona a call ∮
∮ 想要幸福快乐请找费欧娜 ∮
∮ A sporty carriage to ride in style, Sexy man boy chauffeur, Kyle ∮
∮ 一辆外表不逊的马车 性感马夫来相爱 ∮
∮ Banish your blemishes, tooth decay, Cellulite thighs will fade away ∮
∮ 还帮你去除掉赤斑蛀牙更美白 粽子老皮别缠我... ∮
∮ And oh, what the hey! Have a bichon frise! ∮
∮ 真是万岁! 给你一些宝贝! ∮
∮ Nip and tuck, here and there to land that prince with the perfect hair ∮
∮ 揉揉眼  松松肩 梳梳头发让王子迷恋 ∮
∮ Lipstick liners, shadows blush To get that prince with the sexy tush ∮
∮ 口红鲜艳眼影细  还有王子性感的小动作 ∮
∮ Lucky day, hunk buffet You and your prince take a roll in the hay ∮
∮ 别浪费好机会 你和王子一起比翼双飞 ∮
∮ You can spoon on the moon With the prince to the tune ∮
∮ 数一数  小珍珠 这一生  相撕守 ∮
∮ Don't be drab, you'll be fab Your prince will have rock-hard abs ∮
∮ 别害臊  会更好 同受爱情的美妙 ∮
∮ Cheese souffle, Valentine's Day Have some chicken fricassee ∮
∮ 情人节爱情夜 来点烧味更点缀 ∮
∮ Nip and tuck, here and there To land that prince with the perfect hair ∮
∮ 揉揉眼  松松肩 梳梳头发让王子迷恋... ∮
Stop!
停!
Look...
听我说...
Thank you very much, Fairy Godmother,
非常谢谢你神仙教母
but I really don't need all this.
可是  这些我都不需要
Fine. Be that way. We didn't like you, anyway.
好了  随便你  反正我们也不喜欢你
Fiona?
费欧娜?
费欧娜!
Oh! You got a puppy? All I got in my room was shampoo.
你房间还送小狗? 我的房间只送沐浴露耶!
Fairy Godmother,
神仙教母
furniture...
各位家具...
I'd like you to meet my husband, Shrek.
我来介绍我的老公... 史瑞克
Your husband?
老公?!
What? What did you say?
你说什么!?
When did this happen?
这是什么时候发生的事?
Shrek is the one who rescued me.
因为史瑞克他救了我
But that can't be right.
但是不应该是这样啊!
Oh, great, more relatives!
太好了! 又多了一个亲戚!
She's just trying to help.
她是来帮我们的
Good! She can help us pack.
她可以帮忙打包
Get your coat, dear. We're leaving.
去拿衣服  我们走人了
What?  I don't want to leave.
什么?   走人? 我才不想走.
When did you decide this?
你什么时候决定的?
Shortly after arriving.
从我一来就决定了
Look, I'm sorry...
我很抱歉.
No, that's all right. I need to go, anyway.
不用不用 不用道歉  反正我也要走了
But remember, dear.
不过要记得啊
If you should ever need me...
只要你需要我...
happiness... is just a teardrop away.
幸福... 只需要一滴眼泪
Thanks, but we've got all the happiness we need.
谢了  我们现在已经很幸福了
Happy, happy, happy...
幸福幸福好幸福...
So I see.
看得出来...
Let's go, Kyle.
我们走吧
-  Very nice, Shrek. - What?
-  你看你干的好事 - 怎么啦?
I told you coming here was a bad idea.
我早就说过我们不该来的
You could've at least tried to get along with my father.
你至少可以先试着 跟我父王好好相处啊
I don't think I was going to get Daddy's blessing,
拜托  就算我愿意想跟他好好相处
even if I did want it.
你父王也不见得愿意啊
Do you think it might be nice if somebody asked me what I wanted?
那你有没想过...问问我? 看我到底想要什么?
Sure. Do you want me to pack for you?
有啊  请问要我帮你打包吗?
You're unbelievable!
你真是不可理喻!
You're behaving like a...
你简直野蛮得象个...
Go on! Say it!
说啊说啊...
Like an ogre!
像个妖物!
Here's a news flash for you!
你脑子清醒一点...
Whether your parents like it or not... I am an ogre!
不管你父母接不接受  我就是个妖怪!
And guess what, Princess? That's not about to change.
我再告诉你  公主 这是谁也没办法改变的
I've made changes for you, Shrek. Think about that.
我可是为你做了改变  史瑞克  你自己想想吧
That's real smooth, Shrek. "I'm an ogre!"
你好威风哦  史瑞克 "我就是个妖物..."
I knew this would happen.
我就知道会这样!
You should. You started it.
那当然了  都是你引起的
I can hardly believe that, Lillian.
我真不敢相信你会这么说
He's the ogre. Not me.
你想想  妖怪是他又不是我!
I think, Harold, you're taking this a little too personally.
哈洛  你不觉得你管得也太多了嘛
This is Fiona's choice.
这是费欧娜自己的选择
But she was supposed to choose the prince we picked for her.
没错  可是她应该选择 我们帮她挑的王子
I mean, you expect me to give my blessings to this... thing?
难道你真的希望我祝福... 这...这个...妖怪?
Fiona does.
费欧娜希望啊
And she'll never forgive you if you don't.
你不这么做  她绝不会原谅你
I don't want to lose our daughter again, Harold.
我不想再失去我们的女儿了  哈咯!
Oh, you act as if love is totally predictable.
难道你忘了... 爱情都是不可预测的吗?
Don't you remember when we were young?
你忘了... 当我们年轻的时候
We used to walk down by the lily pond and...
我们在水莲池畔散步...
they were in bloom...
花儿朵朵绽放
Our first kiss.
我们的初吻
It's not the same!
可是这不一样
I don't think you realize that our daughter
你难道还不明白我们的女儿...
has married a monster!
是嫁给了怪物吗?!
Oh, stop being such a drama king.
不要把他当怪物就好了嘛
Fine! Pretend there's nothing wrong!
很好!很好! 我们就假装一切都很完美
Isn't it all wonderful! I'd like to know how it could get any worse!
真是完美得不得了!  反正再坏还能坏到哪去呢!
Hello, Harold.
你好  哈洛.
What happened?
你又怎么了?
Nothing, dear!
没什么 没什么...
Just the old crusade wound playing up a bit!
只是我的老毛病又犯了!
I'll just stretch it out here for a while.
我到外面去做做伸展运动啊
You better get in.
你最好进来
We need to talk.
我们需要聊一聊
Actually, Fairy Godmother, off to bed.
老实说  神仙教母... 我已经要睡觉了
Already taken my pills, and they tend to make me a bit drowsy.
我连安眠药都吃  现在整个人昏昏沉沉的
So, how about... we make this a quick visit.
所以...不过... 我们可以长话短说
What?
...干嘛?
Oh, hello. Ha-ha-ha!
...你好
So, what's new?
怎么  有什么事啊?
You remember my son, Prince Charming?
你还记得我的儿子... 白马王子?
Is that you? My gosh! It's been years.
帅哥...真的是你? 天那...好多年没见了
When did you get back?
你... 你什么时候回来的?
Oh, about five minutes ago, actually.
大概就在5分钟以前吧
After I endured blistering winds, scorching desert...
就在我忍受刺骨寒风  炽热的沙漠之后
I climbed to the highest room in the tallest tower...
然后我爬上了高塔顶端...
Mommy can handle this.
冷静冷静冷静  让妈妈来就好了
He endures blistering winds and scorching desert!
他忍受刺骨寒风  还有炽热的沙漠之后
He climbs to the highest bloody room of the tallest bloody tower...
爬上了该死的最高塔里头  最该死的那间房间...
- But... - And what does he find?
-  可是... - 你猜猜他看到了什么?
Some gender-confused wolf
他看见一只 不男不女的大野狼...
telling him that his princess
跟他说  公主...
is already married.
...已经结婚了
It wasn't my fault. He didn't get there in time.
可是这不是我的错  是帅哥动作太慢了
Stop the car!
给我停车!
Harold.
哈洛
You force me to do something I really don't want to do.
这次可是你逼我做出 我真的不想做的事情!
Where are we?
我们到哪了?
Hi. Welcome to Friar's Fat Boy! May I take your order?
你们好!欢迎来到"麦当鸡"  请问要点些什么?
My diet is ruined! I hope you're happy. Er... okay.
你害我减肥失败  这下你高兴了吧
Two Renaissance Wraps, no mayo... chili rings...
我要两个香鸡卷 不要梅奶汁  我还要炸盐鸡...
I'll have the Medieval Meal.
我还要点快乐儿童餐
One Medieval Meal and, Harold...Curly fries?
一份快乐儿童餐  哈洛  要薯条吗?
No, thank you.
啊...我不用  谢谢
Sourdough soft taco, then?
不用装了 要什么就说嘛!
No, really, I'm fine.
我真的不用 我不饿...
Your order, Fairy Godmother.
神仙教母 这是你点的东西.
This comes with the Medieval Meal.
这是快乐儿童餐附赠的
There you are, dear.
这是给你的
We made a deal, Harold,
哈洛  我们都讲好了对不对?
and I assume you don't want me to go back on my part.
我想你应该 也不希望我反悔吧
Indeed not.
当然不希望
So, Fiona and Charming will be together.
所以  换句话说  费欧娜一定会嫁给我儿子啰?
Yes.
是啊
Believe me, Harold. It's what's best.
相信我! 哈洛  这是最好的选择
Not only for your daughter...
不只对你的女儿好...
but for your Kingdom.
对整个王国都好
What am I supposed to do about it?
可是我应该怎么做呢?
Use your imagination.
用用你的脑袋想一想
(毒苹果酒吧)
Come on in, Your Majesty.
请进吧   国王陛下
∮ I like my town ∮
∮ 我喜欢我的城镇 ∮
∮ With a little drop of poison ∮
∮ 来一点毒药 ∮
∮ Nobody knows... ∮
∮ 没有人知道... ∮
Excuse me.
不好意思...
Do I know you?
我好像看过你?
No, you must be mistaking me for someone else.
呃...不可能吧  你一定是认错人了.
Uh... excuse me. I'm looking for the Ugly Stepsister.
呃...不好意思  我要找灰姑娘的丑姐姐
Ah! There you are. Right.
啊...就是你啊...
You see, I need to have someone taken care of.
是这样的  我想要找人 帮我解决一个人
Who's the guy?
解决什么人?
Well, he's not a guy, per se.
也不能算是人了... 他是...
Um... He's an ogre.
他是个...妖怪
Hey, buddy, let me clue you in.
老头  老实跟你说
There's only one fellow who can handle a job like that, and, frankly...
全王国只有一个家伙 能干这种事
he don't like to be disturbed.
但是 他不喜欢人家打扰他
Where could I find him?
呃... 要去哪找他?
Hello?
呃... 你好?
Who dares enter my room?
谁这么大胆敢进我房间...
Sorry! I hope I'm not interrupting,
对不起  希望没有打扰到你
but I'm told you're the one to talk to about an ogre problem?
我听说你可以解决关于... 妖怪的问题?
You are told correct.
你说的没错...
But for this, I charge a great deal of money.
不过  我的收费可是很高的哦
Would... this be enough?
这些... 够吗?
You have engaged my valuable services, Your Majesty.
我将为你献上... 我物超所值的服务...
Just tell me where I can find this ogre.
告诉我 这个妖怪在哪里...
∮ Everyone says I'm getting down too low ∮
∮ 每个人都知道  我的心情跌落谷底 ∮
∮ Everyone says you've just gotta let it go ∮
∮ 所有人都劝我  别想这么多 ∮
∮ You just gotta let it go ∮
∮ 算了吧  别想这么多 ∮
∮ I need some sleep ∮
∮ 我累了  需要一点时间睡 ∮
∮ Time to put the old horse down ∮
∮ 也该让马儿休息了 ∮
∮ I'm in too deep ∮
∮ 我陷入沉思 ∮
∮ And the wheels keep spinning round ∮
∮ 车轮飞快地转动着 ∮
∮ Everyone says you've just gotta let it go ∮
∮ 所有人都劝我  别想这么多 ∮
Dear Knight, I pray that you take this favor as a token of my gratitude.
亲爱的骑士  希望你能接受这个礼物  让我表达我的感激
Dear Diary...
亲爱的日记
Sleeping Beauty is having a slumber party tomorrow,
睡美人明天要办通宵派对
but Dad says I can't go.
可是父王说我不可以去
He never lets me out after sunset.
太阳下山以后  他都不让我出去
Dad says I'm going away for a while.
父王说 我必须离开这一阵子
Must be like some finishing school.
大概是要我去念技术学校吧
Mom says that when I'm old enough,
母后说 等我长大了
my Prince Charming will rescue me from my tower
英俊的白马王子 就会到塔里来救我
and bring me back to my family,
把我带回家里团聚
and we'll all live happily ever after.
从此过着幸福快乐的日子
Mrs. Fiona Charming.
我要嫁给白马王子
白马王子太太
Mrs. Fiona Charming.
白马王子太太...
Sorry. I hope I'm not interrupting anything.
对不起  希望我没有嘈到你
No, no. I was just reading a, uh...
没有没有  我正看...
A scary book.
...恐怖小说
I was hoping you'd let me apologize for my despicable behavior earlier.
我刚才的态度非常恶劣  我希望你能接受我的道歉
Okay...
道歉?
I don't know what came over me.
我是一时糊涂才会这样
Do you suppose we could pretend it never happened and start over...
我愿意当作一切都没有发生  让我们从头开始...
Look, Your Majesty, I just...
国王陛下...
Please. Call me Dad.
不不不... 请叫我父王
Dad
父王
We both acted like ogres.
我们俩个态度都不好
Maybe we just need some time to get to know each other.
或许我们需要多一点 时间好好了解对方
Excellent idea!
说得太好了
I was actually hoping you might join me for a morning hunt.
我正希望你明天早上 能跟我一起去打猎
A little father-son time?
享受父子亲密时间...
I know it would mean the world to Fiona.
我想费欧娜 一定会很开心
Shall we say, 7:30 by the old oak?
那我们就约好 早上七点半在榕树下见
Face it, Donkey! We're lost.
不要硬撑了  我们迷路了
We can't be lost. We followed the King's instructions exactly.
怎么可能会迷路 我们完全是按照国王的指示呀
"Head to the darkest part of the woods..."
他怎么说的 往树林里最远最暗的方向走...
"Past the sinister trees with scary-looking branches."
你会经过一堆长得 像姚明那么高的树...
The bush shaped like Shirley Bassey!
然后会看到像 小亮哥那么矮的树...
We passed that three times already!
那个地方 我们已经走过三遍了!
You were the one who said not to stop for directions.
是你自己不想 找人问路的好吗?
Oh, great.
噢...太好了
My one chance to fix things up with Fiona's dad
我好不容易有机会可以跟 费欧娜的父王合好
and I end up lost in the woods with you!
结果我却跟你在森林里迷路!
Don't get huffy! I'm only trying to help.
你干吗把气出在我身上? 我只是想帮忙啊
I know! I know.
我了... 我了...
I'm sorry, all right?
对不起  好吗?
Hey, don't worry about it.
好了  我也没有怪你
I just really need to make things work with this guy.
我真的很希望 能跟她的父王好好相处
Yeah, sure. Now let's go bond with Daddy.
就这样  我们快点去找岳父大人吧
Well, well, well, Donkey.
驴子...
I know it was kind of a tender moment back there, but the purring?
我知道你想化解尴尬的气氛  可是你也不用出怪声吧
What? I ain't purring.
你都秀逗了  我哪有?
Sure. What's next? A hug?
别撑了  你是不是又想...抱抱啊?
Hey, Shrek. Donkeys don't purr. What do you think I am, some kind of a...
童话驴子哪会出这种怪声? 你把我当成是什么...
Ha-ha! Fear me, if you dare!
啊哈... 够胆的话就不必怕我
Look! A little cat.
你看! 有只小猫耶
Look out, Shrek! He got a piece!
小心! 史瑞克! 他有家伙!
It's a cat, Donkey. Come here, little kitty, kitty.
不过是只猫  驴子 来啊...来来来...
Come on, little kitty. Come here. Oh! Come here, little kitty.
快过来 小猫咪...来啊... 快过来...小猫咪...
Hold on, Shrek! I'm coming!
别怕! 史瑞克  我来救你了
Come on!
快!
Get it off!
把他弄走!
Get it off!Oh, God. Oh...No
弄...弄走!
Look out, Shrek!
史瑞克!小心!
Get it off!
弄走!
Hold still!   Shrek! Hold still!
史瑞克! 别动! 史瑞克!
Did I miss?
中了吗?
No.
中了...
You got them.
正中要害...
Now, ye ogre, pray for mercy from...
求饶吧  妖怪
Puss...
我乃大名鼎鼎的...
in Boots!
...靴猫剑客
I'll kill that cat!
我要杀了你这只猫!
Hairball.
噎到毛了
Oh! That is nasty!
真的好恶心哦!
What should we do with him?
你觉我们该怎么解决它?
Take the sword and neuter him.
我觉得拿它的剑 把小鸡鸡割掉好了
Give him the Bob Barker treatment.
以免野猫越来越多
Oh, no! Por favor! Please!
妈妈咪呀  我求求你
I implore you! It was nothing personal, Senor.
我拜托你  不要把私人恩怨给扯进来
I was doing it only for my family.My mother, she is sick.
我这么做都是为了家人  我上有高堂老母...
And my father lives off the garbage!
我老爸过着吃垃圾的日子 我还有很多弟妹要养...
The King offered me much in gold and I have a litter of brothers...
国王要给我一大笔钱  要我...
Fiona's father paid you to do this?
等一等...费欧娜的父王 给你钱叫你来杀我?
The rich King? Si.
凯子国王? 是啊
Well, so much for Dad's royal blessing.
看来  父王的祝福我是无福消受了
Don't feel bad.
喔 史瑞克. 看开点嘛
Almost everybody that meets you wants to kill you.
反正不管谁看到你都想杀你
Gee, thanks.
谢谢你了
Maybe Fiona would've been better off
如果我是白马王子
if I were some sort of Prince Charming.
大概就可以 让费欧娜好过一点吧
That's what the King said.
是啊  国王就是这么说的
Oh, uh... sorry. I thought that question was directed at me.
呃...抱歉  就当我刚刚什么都没说
Shrek, Fiona knows you'd do anything for her.
史瑞克  费欧娜知道 你对她用情很深
Well, it's not like I wouldn't change if I could.
如果真的要我改  我也不是不能改
I just... I just wish I could make her happy.
我真的... 我真的希望我能让她开心
Hold the phone...
等一下...
"Happiness".
幸福...
"A tear drop away".
只需要一滴眼泪
Donkey! Think of the saddest thing that's ever happened to you!
驴子  赶快想想 你这辈子最难过的事
Aw, man, where do I begin?
喔... 你要我从何说起好呢?
First there was the time that old farmer tried to sell me for some magic beans.
目屎流不停啊! 有一天父子俩个牵着我
Then this fool had a party
本来一起走得好好的
and he have the guests trying to pin the tail on me.
一下子老爸上来骑我  一下子又换儿子上来骑我
Then they got drunk
被这样轮完以后...
and start beating me with a stick,
干脆两个人上来骑
going "Pinata!!"
你以为想骑就骑哦
What is a pinata, anyway?
我怎么这么没面子啊
No, Donkey! I need you to cry!
不是啊  驴子 我要你掉眼泪!
Don't go projecting on me.
哦... 我好好的干吗要掉眼泪?
I know you're feeling bad, but you got to...
我知道你难过  但是你...
You little, hairy, litter-licking sack of...
你这只心肠狠毒的猫...
What? Is it on? Is it on?
开始录了吗? 开始了吗?
This is Fairy Godmother.
我是神仙教母
I'm either away from my desk or with a client.
我现在没有办法 接听你的电话
But if you come by the office,
如果你想找我 做心理咨询
we'll be glad to make you an appointment.
我很乐意跟你 约时间谈谈你的问题
Have a "happy ever after. "
要幸福快乐哦
Are you up for a little quest, Donkey?
想不想去做点 心理咨询啊  驴子?
That's more like it!
好啊! 这还差不多...
Shrek and Donkey, on another whirlwind adventure!
驴子跟史瑞克 又要再度出发冒险了!
∮ Ain't no stoppin' us now! Whoo! We're on the move! ∮
∮ 我们一起走... 你别挡路... ∮
Stop, Ogre!
等一下  妖怪!
I have misjudged you.
我要对你另眼相看!
Join the club. We've got jackets.
少说屁话  要么就加入
On my honor,
这是我的荣幸
I am obliged to accompany you until I have saved your life
在下比尔... 为了报答你的饶命之恩
as you have spared me mine.
我会竭尽所能帮你
The position of annoying talking animal has already been taken.
想死啊...最会打屁扯蛋的 动物就是我了 不需要你了...
Let's go, Shrek.
我们走  史瑞克!
Shrek?
史瑞克?
-  Shrek! - Aw, come on, Donkey. Look at him...
- 史瑞克! - 不要这样嘛  驴子  你看看他
in his wee little boots.
还穿可爱的小鞋鞋
You know, how many cats can wear boots? Honestly.
世上有多少猫是穿鞋子的? 对不对?
Let's keep him!
我们需要他嘛
Say what?
真可笑耶
Listen. He's purring!
这声音好可爱哦
Oh, so now it's cute.
可爱个屁!
Come on, Donkey. Lighten up.
不要这样  驴子  开心一点嘛
Lighten up?
开心?
Lighten up? I should lighten up?
心情不好的人叫 心情好的人开心?
Look who's telling who to lighten up!
笑死人了
Shrek!
史瑞克...
Shrek?
史瑞克?
They're both festive, aren't they?
这两块布料看起来蛮喜气的
What do you think, Harold?
对不对  哈洛?
Um... Yes, yes. Fine. Fine.
呃...对对... 喜气...喜气...
Try to at least pretend you're interested in your daughter's wedding ball.
就算你不关心你女儿的婚礼  可是好歹也要假装一下嘛
Honestly, Lillian, I don't think it matters.
老实说  莉雅  我会觉得我无所谓
How do we know there will even be a ball?
说不定他们根本 就不打算来参加
Mom. Dad.
母后  父王
Oh, hello, dear.
早安  亲爱的
What's that, Cedric? Right! Coming.
呃...你说什么? 好好好...我来了...
Mom, have you seen Shrek?
母后  你有看到史瑞克吗?
I haven't. You should ask your father.
没有耶  你应该去问你的父王
Be sure and use small words, dear.
尽量讲得慢一点  简单一点
He's a little slow this morning.
他今天早上有点迟钝
Can I help you, Your Majesty?
需要什么吗  国王陛下?
Mmm! Exquisite. What do you call this dish?
啊...要...太好吃了  这是什么菜啊?
That would be the dog's breakfast, Your Majesty.
这是要拿去给狗吃的早餐  国王陛下
Ah, yes. Very good, then. Carry on, Cedric.
呃...对  非常好  快端去吧
Dad? Dad, have you seen Shrek?
父王  你有看到史瑞克吗?
No, I haven't, dear.
呃...没看来
I'm sure he just went off to look for a nice...
我想他大概是 躲到哪避风头去了
mud hole to cool down in.
免得跟你起冲突
You know, after your little spat last night.
你们俩个  昨天晚上嗓门还真大
Oh. You heard that, huh?
你都听到啦?
The whole kingdom heard you.
全国的人都听到了
I mean, after all, it is in his nature to be...
我是说  毕竟这是他的本性...
well, a bit of a brute.
怎么说呢  本性就粗鲁
Him?
你说他?
You know, you didn't exactly roll out the Welcome Wagon.
老实说... 你对他的态度也很不友善
Well, what did you expect? Look at what he's done to you.
你还要我怎么样? 你看看他把你弄成什么样子了?
Shrek loves me for who I am.
不管我是什么样子  他都会爱我
I would think you'd be happy for me.
我还以为你会替我高兴呢
Darling, I'm just thinking about what's best for you.
我满脑子在想  怎么做才对你最好?
Maybe you should do the same.
也许你也该为自己打算一下
No, really?
喔...真的吗
Oh, no. That's the old Keebler's place. Let's back away slowly.
这是什么鬼房子啊? 我们还是快闪吧
That's the Fairy Godmother's cottage.
那是神仙教母的房子
She's the largest producer of hexes and potions in the whole kingdom.
这个地方是远得要命王国 最大的魔药制造厂
Then why don't we pop in there for a spell?
那还不快进去 请她帮我们...
Ha-ha! Spell!
...做法啊...
He makes me laugh.
大哥  你还真幽默啊
Hi. I'm here to see the...
嗨! 我是来找...
The Fairy Godmother.
仙女教母
I'm sorry. She is not in.
很抱歉  她不在
Jerome! Coffee and a Monte Cristo.
杰罗  我要咖啡和火鸡三明治
Now!
快点!
Yes, Fairy Godmother. Right away.
是  神仙教母  马上来!
Look, she's not seeing any clients today, OK?
她今天不打算见客! 好吗?
That's OK, buddy. We're from the union.
无所谓  兄弟  我们是工会来的.
The union?
工会?
We represent the workers
我们几个呢...
in all magical industries, both evil and benign.
是魔法与魔术工会 所派来的代表
Oh! Oh, right.
噢! 是
Are you feeling at all degraded or oppressed?
你会不会觉得在这里 不受重视而且被压榨呢?
Uh... a little.
呃...有一点
We don't even have dental.
我们甚至连健保都没有
They don't even have dental.
他们连健保都没有
Okay, we'll just have a look around.
好了  我们要到处看一看了
Oh. By the way.
对了...
I think it'd be better if the Fairy Godmother didn't know we were here.
我觉得不要让神仙教母 知道我们在这里比较好
Know what I'm saying?
你知道我的意思吧?
-  Stop it. - Of course. Go right in.
- 够了 - 当然了  进去吧
A drop of desire.
一滴...欲望
Naughty!
噢...好坏哦
A pinch of passion.
一点...热情
And just a hint of...Iust!
再来一些些... 忘情水
Excuse me.
不好意思
Sorry to barge in like this...
抱歉  这样闯进来  可是...
What in Grimm's name are you doing here?
你这个妖怪  跑到这来干什么?
Well, it seems that Fiona's not exactly happy.
因为... 费欧娜看起来好像不开心
And there's some question as to why that is?
公主遇上妖怪 不会有好下场的
Well, let's explore that, shall we?
好  我来帮你找找看
Ah.
啊  这...
P, P, P... Princess. Cinderella.
公主篇... 灰姑娘!
Here we are. "Lived happily ever after." Oh...
呃... 从此过着幸福快乐的日子
No ogres!
喔...没有妖怪
Let's see. Snow White.
再看看  白雪公主..
A handsome prince. Oh, no ogres.
英俊的王子 喔... 没有怪物
Sleeping Beauty. Oh, no ogres!
睡美人 喔...没有怪物
Hansel and Gretel? No!
糖果屋... 没有
Thumbelina? No.
姆指姑娘... 没有
The Golden Bird, the Little Mermaid, Pretty Woman...
黄金鸟  小美人鱼  小妇人...
No, no, no, no, no! You see,
没有! 没有! 没有! 通通没有! 你看...
ogres don't live happily ever after.
所有幸福快乐的故事里 都没有妖怪
All right, look, lady!
老太婆  你给我听着...
Don't you point... those dirty green sausages at me!
不要用你又肥又脏的 垃圾甜不辣手指着我
Your Monte Cristo and coffee. Oh! Sorry.
您的火鸡三明治和咖啡  喔... 对不起
Ah... that's okay.We were just leaving.
啊...没关系  我们刚好也要走了
Very sorry to have wasted your time, Miss Godmother.
很抱歉浪费您这么多时间  仙女教母
Just... go.
算了...走吧
Come on, guys.
好  我们走了
TGlF, eh, buddy?
辛苦了  老兄
Working hard or hardly working, eh, Mac?
要认真工作不要偷懒哦
(药水室)
Get your fine Corinthian footwear
拜托  你跟你的臭鞋子...
and your cat cheeks out of my face!
还有你的大屁股 离我远一点好吗?
Man, that stinks!
真是恶心耶!
You don't exactly smell like a basket of roses.
你屁股闻起来 还不是有一股驴屎味
Well, one of these has got to help.
这里其中的一种药 肯定有效
I was just concocting this very plan!
哎呀! 我也刚好这么想
Already our minds are becoming one.
没想到我们真有 心有灵犀一点通耶
Whoa, whoa.
少在这里肉麻当有趣了
If we need an expert on licking ourselves, we'll give you a call.
下次我们需要 马屁精的时候再找你
Shrek, this is a bad idea.
史瑞克  这点子很逊耶
Look. Make yourself useful and go keep watch.
拜托  闭上你的驴嘴  到门口去守着
Puss, do you think you could get to those on top?
靴猫  你有办法能爬到最上面吗?
No problema, boss.
没问题  大佬
In one of my nine lives,I was the great cat
我的另外一个外号 就叫蜘蛛猫
burglar of Santiago de Compostela.
最擅长的就是爬101大楼
Shrek, are you off your nut?
史瑞克  你是不是疯了
Donkey, keep watch.
驴子  看门去
Keep watch? Yeah, I'll keep watch.
看门去? 好 让我看就去看...
I'll watch that wicked witch come
我就要看那个邪恶的巫婆 把你关到养得肥肥胖胖的
and whammy a world of hurt up your backside.
然后煮来吃
I'll laugh, too. I'll be giggling to myself.
到时候我就在旁边大笑  笑到肚子痛...
What do you see?
看到什么了?
Toad Stool Softener?
癞蛤蟆泄药
I'm sure a nice
帅喔  你还真聪明耶
BM is the perfect solution for marital problems
那你干脆找一瓶能 增进夫妻之间幸福的药
Elfa Seltzer?
知识糖浆?
Hex Lax?
通便剂?
No! Try "handsome."
不是  有没有帅哥药?
Sorry. No handsome.
抱歉  没有帅哥药
Hey! How about "Happily Ever After"?
嘿! 可是有... 幸福快乐神仙水?
Well, what does it do?
呃... 那是干什么用的?
It says "Beauty Divine."
上面写 "快速美丽"
In some cultures, donkeys are revered as the wisest of creatures.
你知道吗? 在某些文化里头  把驴子当做是最聪明的动物
Especially us talking ones.
尤其是会说话的驴子
Donkey!
驴子!
That'll have to do. We've got company.
就拿那那个吧 有人来了!
Can we get on with this?
你就是不死心啊
Hurry!
快啊
Nice catch, Donkey!
接的好  驴子.
Finally! A good use for your mouth.
不简单啊  你这驴嘴终于有点用了!
Come on!
快跑!
∮ You spurn my natural emotions ∮
∮ 你无视我的感情 ∮
∮ You make me feel like dirt and I'm hurt ∮
∮ 视我如粪土  教我肝肠寸断 ∮
∮ And if I start a commotion ∮
∮ 如果我开始动摇 ∮
∮ I run the risk of losing you and that's worse ∮
∮ 就得冒失去她的危险  结局反而更糟 ∮
∮ Ever fallen in love with someone, ever fallen in love ∮
∮ 曾经爱上一个人  刻苦铭心... ∮
∮ In love with someone, ever fallen in love ∮
∮ 爱上了某人  刻苦铭心... ∮
∮ In love with someone you shouldn 't have fallen in love with ∮
∮ 一个不该爱的人 ∮
∮ Ever fallen in love with someone, ever fallen in love ∮
∮ 曾经爱上一个人  曾经爱上... ∮
∮ In love with someone, ever fallen in love ∮
∮ 一个人  曾经爱上... ∮
∮ With someone you shouldn 't have fallen in love with ∮
∮ 一个不该爱的人 ∮
∮ Fallen in love with ∮
∮ 曾经爱上... ∮
∮ Ever fallen in love with someone you shouldn 't have fallen in love with ∮
∮ 曾经爱上一个 不该爱的人刻苦铭心 ∮
I don't care whose fault it is.
我现在不打算追究责任
Just get this place cleaned up!
快点把这里给我清干净
Fairy Godmother
是  教母
And somebody
还有  不管是谁
bring me something deep fried and smothered in chocolate!
快点去拿点甜死人 的巧克力来给我
Mother!
妈咪
Charming. Sweetheart.
儿子  我亲爱的!
This isn't a good time, pumpkin. Mama's working.
你来得真不是时候  妈妈正在忙呢
Whoa, what happened here?
哇! 这里发生什么事了?
The ogre, that's what!
都要怪那只妖怪!
What?
什么!
Where is he, Mom?
他在哪?
I shall rend his head from his shoulders!
我一定要让他跪地求饶!
I will smite him where he stands!
我要打到他四肢无力!
He will rue the very day he stole my kingdom from me!
我要让他每天都后悔 抢走我的王国
Oh, put it away, Junior! You're still going to be king.
不要激动  年轻人  你一定会当上国王的
We'll just have to come up with something smarter.
我们只要好好 想个办法就行了
Pardon. Um...Everything is accounted for,
打扰一下  我已经清点完毕了
Fairy Godmother,except for one potion.
神仙教母  只有神仙水不见了
What?
什么?
I do believe we can make this work to our advantage.
这下子我们的机会来了
"Happily Ever After Potion. Maximum strength.
幸褔快乐神仙水... 上面写药效惊人耶
"For you and your true love.
你跟你的真爱
"If one of you drinks this,
只要其中一个人喝下
you both will be fine. "Happiness, comfort and beauty divine."
你们从此就 会过着幸福快乐的日子
You both will be fine?
对两个人都有效?
I guess it means it'll affect Fiona, too.
我想这对费欧娜也应该有用
Hey, man, this don't feel right.
嘿...我总觉得怪怪的
My donkey senses are tingling all over.
我的驴子第六感觉很不舒服
Drop that jug o' voodoo and let's get out of here.
赶快把这个神仙水丢掉 一起离开这个鬼地方
It says, "Beauty Divine." How bad can it be?
上头说它"快速美丽" 看看它有多快嘛
See, you're allergic to that stuff. You'll have a reaction.
你对这个东西会过敏  一定会出大事了
And if you think that I'll be smearing Vapor Rub over your chest,
万一你挂了 你这么肥  我可没有办法抬你回去哦
think again!
再考虑一下
Boss, just in case there is something wrong with the potion...
老大  你要考虑不伤身再求药效
allow me to take the first sip.
不如让小弟先帮你喝一口
It would be an honor to lay my life on the line for you.
能够为你牺牲性命 是我天大的荣幸
Oh, no, no.
噢...不行不行
I don't think so.
我可不这么认为哦
If there'll be any animal testing,
如果真的要进行动物实验
I'll do it.
那也应该我来才对啊
That's the best friend's job. Now give me that bottle.
什么叫做好朋友呢  把瓶子给我...
How do you feel?
有什么感觉?
I don't feel any different.
我没有什么感觉啊
I look any different?
有变吗?
You still look like an ass to me.
你看起来还是很驴啊
Maybe it doesn't work on donkeys.
说不定这药对驴子没用
Well, here's to us, Fiona.
好吧... 为了我们幸福费欧娜
Shrek?
史瑞克!
You drink that, there's no going back.
喝了以后  你就不能再回头啰
I know.
我知道
-  No more wallowing in the mud? - I know.
- 以后就再也不能在沼泽打滚哦 - 我知道
No more itchy butt crack?
你也不能再树上抓痒哦
I know!
我知道
But you love being an ogre!
可是你当妖怪当得很爽耶
I know!
我知道!!!
But I love Fiona more.
可是我更爱费欧娜
Shrek, no! Wait!
史瑞克  不要冲动
Got to be...
噢...臭...臭滚滚
I think you grabbed the "Farty Ever After" potion.
你喝的该不会是 快速放屁药水吧
Maybe it's a dud.
大概过期了
Or maybe Fiona and l were never meant to be.
或许我跟费欧娜 根本不该在一起
Uh-oh. What did I tell you? I feel something coming on.
...我就说有问题嘛  我好像哪里不对劲哦
I don't want to die. I don't want to die. I don't want to die!
我不想死! 我不要死! 我不要死啊...
Oh, sweet sister, mother of mercy. I'm melting!
耶稣 观世音菩萨... 我全身发软!
I'm melting!
我快要融化了...
It's just the rain, Donkey.
下雨而已了  驴子
Don't worry. Things seem bad because it's dark and rainy
史瑞克  看开点  不要因为下雨困在森林里...
and Fiona's father hired a sleazy hitman to whack you.
费欧娜她老爸又找一只 笨猫来杀你而难过嘛
It'll be better in the morning.
明天会更好的
You'll see...
相信我...
∮ The sun'll come out... ∮
∮ 太阳依旧... ∮
∮ Tomorrow ∮
∮ 会升起... ∮
∮ Bet your bottom... ∮
∮ 放手一搏... ∮
Bet my bottom?
放手一搏?
I'm coming, Elizabeth!
啊...我晕了!
Donkey?
驴子?
Are you all right?
你...你没事吧?
Hey, boss. Let's shave him.
老大  我来逗他玩
D-Donkey?
驴...驴子...
There you are! We missed you at dinner.
你来啦! 怎么没来吃晚餐啊
What is it, darling?
什么事啊  亲爱的
Dad...I've been thinking about what you said.
父王  我一直在想你说的话
And I'm going to set things right.
我想我做错了
Ah! Excellent! That's my girl.
啊! 太好了! 这才是我女儿
It was a mistake to bring Shrek here.
我根本不该带史瑞克回来的
I'm going to go out and find him.
我要出去外面找他
And then we'll go back to the swamp where we belong.
然后再一起回到 属于我们的沼泽去
Fiona, please!
费欧娜! 别这样!
Let's not be rash, darling. You can't go anywhere right now.
不要这么急嘛  这么晚了你哪也去不了
Fiona!
费欧娜!
Look, I told you he was here.
你看  我就跟你说他就在这里了嘛
Look at him! Quiet.
嘘...安静一点
Look at him.
你看他...
Good morning, sleepyhead.
早安  爱睡猪
Good morning! We love your kitty!
早安!  我们好喜欢你猫哦
Oh... My head...
噢  头痛死了...
Here, I fetched a pail of water.
来  我帮你把水打好了
Thanks.
喔...谢了
A cute button nose?
帅气的鼻头?
Thick, wavy locks?
又浓又黑的卷发?
Taut, round buttocks?
扎实圆润的屁股?
I'm... I'm...
我...我...
Gorgeous!
好帅啊!
- I'll say. - I'm Jill. What's your name?
- 对啊 - 我是吉儿  你叫什么?
Um... Shrek.
呃...史瑞克
Shrek?
史瑞克?
Wow. Are you from Europe?
哇! 你是上流社会的人啊?
-  You're tense. - I want to rub his shoulders.
-  I got it covered. - I don't have anything to rub.
- 你好紧张哦 - 我帮你按摩吧
- 我来就行了 谢谢! - 那我按哪里啊?
Get in line.
到后面去排队
Have you seen my donkey?
你们有没有看到我的驴子?
Who are you calling donkey?
你叫谁"驴子"?
Donkey? You're a...
驴子?! 你变成...
A stallion, baby! I can whinny.
一匹神驹! 马的呼叫...
I can count.
我会踏步...
Look at me, Shrek!
史瑞克  你看
I'm trotting!
我还会小跑步耶
That's some quality potion. What's in that stuff?
那个药水真神奇  不知道是什么做的?
"Oh, don't take the potion, Mr. Boss, it's very bad."
不知道是哪个驴蛋说: "快把药水丢掉..."
"Warning: Side effects may include burning, itching, oozing, weeping.
"注意  药的副作用有: 发热 发痒 头昏 流泪..."
"Not intended for heart patients or those with... nervous disorders."
"不适合心脏病患者  或情绪不稳定的人喝"
I'm trotting, I'm trotting in place! Yeah!
小跑步小跑步  我会小跑步  耶...
What?
看什么?
Senor? "To make the effects of this potion permanent,
老大  "要让药效长长久久..."
"the drinker must obtain
"喝下这药的人 必须在午夜之前..."
his true love's kiss by midnight."
"...得到真爱的吻"
Midnight? Why is it always midnight?
午夜? 干嘛都规定在午夜?
-  Pick me! I'll be your true love! - I'll be your true love.
- 选我  我是你的真爱 - 我才是你的真爱
I'll be true... enough.
我全身都是...真爱
Look, ladies, I already have a true love.
听好了 美女们  我己经有真爱了
And take it from me, Boss.
老大 我敢担保
You are going to have one satisfied Princess.
公主看到你 一定会满意得不得了
And let's face it. You are a lot easier on the eyes.
呵...好了  面对现实吧
Inside you're the same old mean, salty...
你的确是长得比较帅了  可是骨子里还是土里土气的...
...cantankerous, foul,angry ogre you always been.
你永远是个暴躁下流的 臭熏熏的妖怪...
And you're still the same annoying donkey.
你骨子也还是那头呱噪的驴子
Yeah
对阿!
Well...Look out, Princess. Here comes the new me.
好吧...亲爱的公主  新的史瑞克就要来了
First things first.We need to get you out of those clothes.
嗯...先换掉你的衣服 我想这个才是最重要的
-  Ready? - Ready!
- 好了吗? - 好了!
Driver, stop!
马夫  停车!
Oh, God! Help me, please! My racing days are over!
噢  天啊! 救救我! 我全身上下都动不了了!
I'm blind! Tell the truth.
我瞎了! 我看不见了!
Will I ever play the violin again?
告诉我这辈子 我还能不能拉小提琴?
You poor creature! Is there anything I can do for you?
噢!可怜的小东西  有什么我可以为你做的吗?
Well, I guess there is one thing.
呃... 我想有一件事情你可以帮我
Take off the powdered wig and step away from your drawers.
脱下你的假发 还有你全身上下的衣服
-  Not bad. - Not bad at all.
- 不错嘛 - 真的很不错
Father? Is everything all right, Father?
爸爸... 一切都还好吧?
Thank you, gentlemen!
谢谢你  先生
Someday, I will repay you.
有一天我会报答你的
Unless, of course, I can't find you or if I forget.
除非再也见不到你  或是我忘了
∮ Turn and face the strange, Ch-Ch-Changes ∮
∮ 瞧这些新鲜事  都-都-都变了 ∮
∮ Don't wanna be a richer one ∮
∮ 有钱有什么了不起 ∮
∮ Ch-Ch-Ch-Ch-Changes ∮
∮ 要...改变  换张脸 ∮
∮ Turn and face the strange, Ch-Ch-Changes ∮
∮ 不可思议的改变  要...改变 ∮
∮ Just gonna have to be a different man ∮
∮ 只想要与众不同 ∮
∮ Time may change me,  But I can't trace time ∮
∮ 时间也许可以改变我 但我却留不住它 ∮
Halt!
停!
Tell Princess Fiona
请告诉费欧娜公主
her husband, Sir Shrek, is here to see her.
她的丈夫 史瑞克爵士来看她了
∮ Still don't know what I was looking for ∮
∮ 我仍然懵懵懂懂 ∮
∮ And my time was running wild, a million dead-end streets ∮
∮ 岁月流逝  我却一事无成 ∮
∮ Every time I thought I'd got it made ∮
∮ 每次我以为可以成功 ∮
∮ It seemed the taste was not so sweet ∮
∮ 却总是事与愿违 ∮
∮ Ch-Ch-Ch-Ch-Changes ∮
∮ 啾...全变了 ∮
∮ Turn and face the strange ∮
∮ 瞧这些新鲜事 ∮
- Fiona? - Shrek?
- 费欧娜? - 史瑞克?
∮ Time may change me,  But I can't trace time ∮
∮ 时间也许可以改变我 但我却留不住它 ∮
Fiona?
费欧娜!
Hello, handsome.
你好啊  帅哥
Shrek!
史瑞克!
Princess!
公主!
Donkey?
驴子?!
Wow! That potion worked on you, too?
哇  那个神仙水真的很有用耶
What potion?
什么神仙水啊?
Shrek and I took some magic potion. And well...
这说来话长  史瑞克跟我都喝了神仙水
Now, we're sexy!
现在都变成超级大帅哥了!
Shrek?
史瑞克?
For you, baby... I could be.
宝贝 为了你  我愿意当...
Yeah, you wish.
你想的美!
Donkey, where is Shrek?
史瑞克在哪里?
He went inside looking for you.
他进去里面找你啊?
Shrek?
史瑞克!
Fiona!
费欧娜!
You want to dance, pretty boy?
要不要跳舞啊 帅哥?
Are you going so soon?
干嘛急着走嘛?
Don't you want to see your wife?
你不想看见你太太吗?
Fiona?
费欧娜.
Shrek?
史瑞克?
Aye, Fiona. It is me.
费欧娜  是我
What happened to your voice?
你的声音怎么了?
The potion changed a lot of things, Fiona.
神仙水帮我彻底改变了 费欧娜...
But not the way I feel about you.
可是爱你的心没变
Fiona?
费欧娜?
Charming?
帅哥?
Do you think so?
你也觉得我帅啊?
Dad
父王...
I was so hoping you'd approve.
我一直希望得到您的认同
Um... Who are you?
嗯...你是谁?
Mom, it's me, Shrek.
母后  是我 史瑞克啊
I know you never get a second chance at a first impression,
我知道上次我们见面 你把我当成妖怪
but, well, what do you think?
现在还这么想吗?
Fiona! Fiona!
费欧娜! 费欧娜!!!
Fiona!
费欧娜!
-  Fiona! - Fiona, Fiona! Ho-ho-ho!
- 费欧娜! - 费欧娜...费欧娜!
Oh, shoot! I don't think they can hear us, pigeon.
叫啊  可惜他们听不到  帅哥
Don't you think you've already messed her life up enough?
你不觉你把她 害得还不够惨吗?
I just wanted her to be happy.
我只是希望她能开开心心的
And now she can be.And now she can be.
她现在就很开心啊... 噢...算了吧...
She's finally found the prince of her dreams.
她梦中的王子终于出现了
But look at me. Look what I've done for her.
可是我变成这样... 全是为了她啊
It's time you stop living in a fairy tale, Shrek.
不要活在童话故事里了  史瑞克
She's a princess, and you're an ogre.
她是公主  而你是妖怪
That's something no amount of potion will ever change.
就算你现在这样 也改变不了这个事实
But...I love her.
可是... 我爱她!
If you really love her...you'll let her go.
如果你真的爱她 就让她走吧
Shrek?  Senor.
史瑞克? 老大?
What's going on?
喂  你怎么啦?
Where are you going?
你要去那里?
You wouldn't have had anything to do with this,
这事该不会是 你干的好事吧?
would you, Harold?
是不是  哈洛?
∮ People just ain't no good ∮
∮ 人们并不如想像中善良 ∮
∮ I think that's well understood ∮
∮ 这并不难理解 ∮
There you go, boys.
你的酒来了
Just leave the bottle, Doris.
这明明就不让我留下
Hey. Why the long face?
嘿...干吗这么沮丧?
It was all just a stupid mistake.
我做的这一切真是太笨了
I never should have rescued her from that tower in the first place.
我从一开始就不应该 把她从高塔里救出来
I hate Mondays.
千金难买早知道
I can't believe you'd walk away from the best thing that happened to you.
我真不敢相信你就这样 放弃你最重要的一切
What choice do I have? She loves that pretty boy
我没得选择啊... 她喜欢那个小帅哥
Prince Charming.
什么白马王子...
Come on. Is he really that good-looking?
帮帮忙吧  他哪里有多帅啊?
Are you kidding? He's gorgeous!
你在胡说些什么? 他帅呆了!
He has a face that looks like it was carved by angels.
他的脸简直就是上帝的杰作
Oh. He sounds dreamy.
嗯  他好像很怕他...
You know shockingly, this isn't making me feel any better.
你说他不够帅  我也不见得比较开心啊
Look, guys. It's for the best.
最好的结局  应该就是这样
Mom and Dad approve,and Fiona gets the man she's always dreamed of.
国王王后很喜欢 费欧娜梦中的王子
Everybody wins.
大家都很开心
Except for you. I don't get it, Shrek.
只有你不开心  我真是搞不懂你耶
You love Fiona.
你爱费欧娜啊...
Aye. And that's why I have to let her go.
是啊! 所以我才应该放弃她
Excuse me,
不好意思
- is she here? - She's, uh... in the back.
- 她在里面吗? - 她在...后面
Oh, hello again.
又见面啦
Fairy Godmother. Charming.
神仙教母... 帅哥...
You'd better have a good reason for dragging us down here, Harold.
希望你把我们叫来 是有重要的事  哈洛
Well, I'm afraid Fiona isn't really... warming up to Prince Charming.
我觉得费欧娜好像 还没有准备好...嫁给帅哥
FYl, not my fault.
别赖我哦  我可没错啊
No, of course it's not, dear.
哦...当然  你当然没错
I mean,
how charming can I be when I have to pretend I'm
我是说...
要我这个超帅哥 去演一个丑妖怪
that dreadful ogre?
我要怎么去演嘛?
Perhaps
No, no, it's nobody's fault.
只是... 或许...
不... 这不是错不错的问题
it's best if we just call the whole thing off, okay?
我们应该取消这个计划好吗?
What?
什么?
You can't force someone to fall in love!
我是说... 爱不能勉强的对吧?
I beg to differ. I do it all the time!
这我可不同意  我就常干这种事
Have Fiona drink this
你让费欧娜喝下这个
and she'll fall in love with the first man she kisses,
她就会情不自禁 爱上第一个吻她的人...
which will be Charming.
当然就是我儿子啰
Umm... no.
嗯... 不行!
What did you say?
你在说什么?
I can't. I won't do it.
我...我不要  我不会做
Oh, yes, you will.
你当然会
If you remember, I helped you with your happily ever after.
你应该还记得... 是我让你幸福快乐的
And I can take it away just as easily.
我警告你  我也可以轻易收回这一切
Is that what you want?
你希望我这么做吗?
Is it?
希望吗?
No.
呃...不希望
Good boy. Now, we have to go.
这才乖  好啦  我们该走了
I need to do Charming's hair before the ball.
我还得带我儿子去做头发呢
He can never get to the back.
He's hopeless. He's all high in the front.
前面老是翘起来 后面又乱七八糟
他真是麻烦...
You need someone to do the back.
要找个人帮他整理一下
Oh. Thank you, Mother.
噢...谢谢你  妈咪
Mother?
妈咪!?
Um... Mary! A talking horse!
嗯...看啊! 马也会说话
The ogre!
妖怪!
Stop them! Thieves!
抓住他们! 小偷!
Bandits! Stop them!
强盗! 抓住他们
The abs are fab and it's gluteus to the maximus
完美的肌肉男  请跟随家属的屁股...
here at tonight's Far, Far Away Royal Ball blowout!
来参加今晚 远得要命王国的舞会
The coaches are lined up as the cream of the crop pours out of them
这个王国车水马龙
Like Miss Muffet's curds and whey.
着装精美的人们 前来参加这场美丽的盛会
Everyone who's anyone has turned out
全国知名同胞一起前来向 费欧娜公主跟史瑞克王子致敬
And, oh my, the outfits look gorgeous!
噢! 天那!... 大家打扮得真是争奇斗艳
Look! Hansel and Gretel! What the heck are the crumbs for?
快看! 是汉斯和葛丽娜(糖果屋)  他们还是边走一边撒饼干碎呢
And right behind them, Tom Thumb and Thumbelina!
紧接著在他们后面的是... 姆指姑娘跟姆指汤姆!
Oh, aren't they adorable!
他们好可爱呀!
Here comes Sleeping Beauty!
接下来的是... 睡美人...
Tired old thing.
她永远都是这么累...
Who's this? Who's this? Who is this?
这是谁啊? 谁来了? 是谁啊?
Oh. It's the one, it's the only...It's the Fairy Godmother!
是我们最爱最受欢迎 万民拥戴的...神仙教母...
Hello, Far, Far Away!
大家好! 远的要命王国子民们!!
Can I get a whoop whoop?
我听不到欢呼...
May all your endings be happy and...Well, you know the rest!
祝福大家都幸福美满  还有...你们都知道的了...
We'll be right back with the Royal Far, Far Away Ball
广告之后... 马上回到皇家结婚舞会现场
after these messages.
不要转台哦
I hate these ball shows.They bore me to tears.
我最讨压这些特别节目了  无聊得快死掉了
Flip over to Wheel Of T orture!
我要看前面的  换个台吧
I'm not flipping anywhere, sir,
没水准  我才不要乱转台呢
until I see Shrek and Fiona.
我要看史瑞克跟费欧娜
Whizzes on you guys.
你们这些人很讨压耶!
Hey, mice, pass me a buffalo wing!
老鼠  我要吃鸡翅膀!
No, to your left. Your left!
不是  在你的左边...左边啦!
Tonight on "Knights"...
欢迎收看... 社会追寻...
Now here's a good show!
总算有好节目了
We got a white bronco heading east into the forest.
一匹白色野马往森林逃窜
Requesting backup.
我们需要支援
It's time to teach these madcap mammals
警察大队出动教训这些 以为治安是白设的流氓
their "devil may mare" attitudes just won't fly.
要他们不敢为非作歹
Why you grabbing me? Police brutality!
你凭什么抓我? 警察打人啊!警察打人啊!
- I have to talk to Princess Fiona! - We warned you!
- 让我跟费欧娜公主讲话! - 我警告你...
Did someone let the cat out of the bag?
歹徒会不会逍遥法外呢? 还是真相会站在正义的一方?
You capitalist pig dogs!
你这个资本主义走狗
Catnip!
抓到了...
That's not mine.
这不是我的
Find Princess Fiona!
放开我  我要见费欧娜公主
I'm a donkey!
我是驴子!
Tell her Shrek... I'm her husband, Shrek!
告诉她  我是她丈夫...史瑞克!
Quick!
社会追寻
Rewind it!
快! 快倒带!!
I'm her husband, Shrek! Ow!
告诉她  我是她丈夫...史瑞克!
Darling?
乖女儿?
Ah. I thought I might find you here.
我就知道你会在这里
How about a nice hot cup of tea before the ball?
在参加舞会之前 要不要先喝杯热茶啊?
I'm not going.
我不要参加
The whole Kingdom's turned out to celebrate your marriage.
可是整个国的人 都来庆祝你的婚礼
There's just one problem. That's not my husband.
现在问题是... 那个人根本不是我丈夫
I mean, look at him.
你看看他
Yes, he is a bit different,but people change for the ones they love.
他是有点不一样了 人都会他所爱的人改变
You'd be surprised how much I changed for your mother.
你不知道我为了你母亲 作了多大的改变
Change? He's completely lost his mind!
改变? 他现在这个样子简直是疯了
Why not come down to the ball and give him another chance?
乖女儿你就下去参加舞会 再给他个机会
You might find you like this new Shrek.
说不定你会爱上 这个全新的史瑞克
But it's the old one I fell in love with, Dad.
可是我爱上的是 那个旧的史瑞克
I'd give anything to have him back.
我愿意放弃一切让他变回来
Darling. That's mine. Decaf.
这杯是我的 没咖啡因...
Otherwise I'm up all night.
我怕晚上睡不著...
Thanks.
嗯...谢谢
I got to get out of here!
放我出去!
You can't lock us up like this! Let me go!
你不能把我锁住在这里! 放我走!
What about my Miranda rights?
你们根本没有 审驴子的权利
You're supposed to say I have the right to remain silent.
你应该告诉我 "你有权保持沉默"
Nobody said I have the right to remain silent!
可是却没有人 告诉我这些权力...
You have the right to remain silent.
驴子! 你是有权保持沉默!
What you lack is the capacity.
因为你真的很嘈啊!
I must hold on before l, too, go totally mad.
我必须撑着点  不然我也会跟他一样抓狂
Shrek?
史瑞克?
Donkey?
驴子?
Too late.
太晚了
Gingy! Pinocchio! Get us out of here!
姜饼人! 小木偶! 快救我们出去
Fire in ze hole!
要爆炸啦!
Look out below!
下面小心!
Quick! Tell a lie!
快! 撒个谎!
What should I say?
呃  要我说什么呢?
Anything, but quick!
随便了  快!
Say something crazy like "I'm wearing ladies' underwear!"
要夸张点的  说你穿女生的内衣好了
I am wearing ladies' underwear.
我...我穿了女生的内衣
Are you?
呃...你穿了?
I most certainly am not!
我才没有穿呢!
It looks like you most certainly am are!
你的鼻子告诉我你有穿哦
I am not!
我没有穿!
What kind?
哪一款呢?
It's a thong!!
是雷斯丁的
Oww! They're briefs
我不穿女生的
-  Are not. - Are too!
- 才不是 - 是真的
-  Are not! - Are too!
Here we go. Hang tight.
好  到达了  抓紧哦
Excuse me?
喂...小心点...
What?
干吗?
Puss!
鞋猫!
Pardon me, would you mind letting me go?
求求你让他放了我...
Sorry, boss.
对不起  老大.
Quit messing around! We've got to stop that kiss!
不要再闹了  我们得阻止他们亲嘴!
I thought you was going to let her go.
你不是要放弃费欧娜吗?
I was, but I can't let them do this to Fiona.
没错  可是我不能让他们这样对待她
Boom! That's what I like to hear.
对了! 就是要这样的气魄
Look who's coming around!
你的脑袋终于开窍了
It's impossible! We'll never get in.
这是不可能的 城堡都是守卫
The castle's guarded. There's a moat and everything!
四周还有护城河 我们进不去的
Folks, it looks like we're up chocolate creek without a Popsicle stick.
看样子我们现在就是 少了一座可以过河的桥
What?
看什么?
Do you still know the Muffin Man?
你还记得松饼人住哪吗?
Well, sure! He's down on Drury Lane.
记得 他就住在松饼巷
Why?
干嘛?
Because we're gonna need flour.  Lots and lots of flour.
我们需要面粉 很多很多面粉...
Gingy!
小姜姜!
Fire up the ovens, Muffin Man!
快点开火炉  松饼人
We've got a big order to fill!
有一笔大生意要交给你!
It's alive!
是活的耶...
Run, run, run, as fast you can!
冲... 快冲啊!
Go, baby, go!
冲啊  前进!
There it is, Mongo! To the castle!
就是那样 往城堡走!
No, you great stupid pastry!
不...不对不对 你这个笨饼干!
Come on!
快点!
Mongo! Down here! Look at the pony!
这里! 这里! 跟着我走!
That's right! Follow the pretty pony!
对了对了  跟着我的小马走
Pretty pony wants to play at the castle!
小马要带你到城堡去玩
Pretty pony.
可爱的小马!
Ladies and gentlemen. Presenting Princess Fiona
各位先生女士! 我为你介绍费欧娜公主...
and her new husband, Prince Shrek.
还有她的丈夫... 史瑞克王子!
Shrek, what are you doing?
史瑞克  你在干嘛?
I'm just playing the part, Fiona.
我只是在展现我的魅力
Is that glitter on your lips?
你的嘴巴擦了唇膏吗?
Mm. Cherry flavored. Want to taste?
樱桃口味的 要不要尝尝啊?
Ugh! What is with you?
你到底是怎么了?!
But, Muffin Cake...
我...我没怎么样...
C Minor, put it in C Minor.
C小调 我要C小调
Ladies and gentlemen.
各位先生女士!
I'd like to dedicate this song to...
我要把这首歌献给
Princess Fiona
费欧娜公主...
and Prince Shrek.
还有史瑞克王子
Fiona, my Princess.
费欧娜 亲爱的公主
Will you honor me with a dance?
愿意赏脸跳支舞吗?
∮ Where have all the good men gone ∮
∮ 曾走过的苦难中...啊... ∮
∮ And where are all the gods? ∮
∮ 去哪里追寻... ∮
∮ Where's the streetwise Hercules ∮
∮ 去那曾经追寻过的... 所有的幻想... ∮
∮ To fight the rising odds? ∮
∮ 是否一样的希望... 只存在梦境... ∮
Since when do you dance?
你什么时候会跳舞啦?
Fiona, my dearest, if there's one thing I know,
亲爱的费欧娜  我只能告诉你...
it's that love is full of surprises.
...生命充满了意外惊喜
∮ Late at night I toss and I turn And I dream of what I need ∮
∮ 一整夜  我都辗转难眠 只知道我爱你... ∮
Hit it!
来吧...
∮ I need a Hero... ∮
∮ 我需要英雄 ∮
All right, big fella! Let's crash this party!
好了  大饼  我们准备要冲进去了
Man the catapults!
守护队准备!
Aim! Fire!
瞄准! 发射!
Brace yourselves! Ooh! Purty!
你自己保重啊!
Not the gumdrop button!
大饼  你没事吧? 撑着点...
Incoming!
小心!
Ha-ha! All right!
哈-哈! 帅啊!
∮ Somewhere after midnight In my wildest fantasy ∮
∮ 每到午夜时分  在我狂野的梦里... ∮
Go, Mongo! Go!
走  大饼! 走...
Man the cauldrons!
游击队准备!
After you, Mongo.
你先吧  大饼!
That's it! Heave-ho!
用力! 用力...
Watch out! Shrek!
小心!
More heat, less foam!
再热一点! 把他融掉!
∮ Up where the mountains Meet the heavens above ∮
∮ 整夜同行到天堂里拥抱... ∮
∮ Out where the lightning Splits the sea ∮
∮ 让快乐来临 劈开大海... ∮
∮ I could swear there is someone Somewhere watching me ∮
∮ 我真的感觉到 有人在看着我... ∮
Heave! Ho!
用力!
No...!
不要...!
Come on!
快过来!
Look out!
噢! 大饼...
Be good.
回去吧...
He needs me! Let me go!
放下我! 让我回去...
Donkey!
驴子!
Puss!
鞋猫!
Go! Go! Your lady needs you! Go!
快走  走! 公主需要你  走...
Today, I repay my debt.
今天  让我抛热颅洒热血...
On guard!
啊...看招!
∮ He's gotta be strong And he's gotta be fast ∮
∮ 他浑身是胆... 从不畏惧苦难 ∮
∮ And he's gotta be fresh From the fight ∮
∮ 他为了胜利决战... ∮
∮ I need a Hero... ∮
∮ 我需要英雄... ∮
Stop!
停!
Hey, you! Back away from my wife.
嘿! 你! 快放开我老婆!
Shrek?
史瑞克?
You couldn't just go back to your swamp
你就不能回你的沼泽去 让我们大家...
and leave well enough alone.
...过过好日子吗?
Now!
放射... 炮弹预备!
Pigs und blanket!
猪肉飞弹...
Pinocchio! Get the wand!
小木偶! 快抢下魔杖
I see London! I see France!
我怎么越来越晕啊...
I'm a real boy!
我是真的小男孩!
Catch!
接住!
Donkey!
驴子!
I'm a real boy. Aah!
我是真的小男孩! 噢...
That's mine!
那是我的仙妇棒...
Pray for mercy, from Puss...
叛徒克星  靴猫...
And Donkey!
还有驴子!
She's taken the potion! Kiss her now!
她已经喝了药水了! 快点亲她!
No!
不要..!
Fiona.
费欧娜
Shrek.
史瑞克
Harold! You were supposed to give her the potion!
哈洛! 你不是已经给她吃过药了吗?
Well, I guess I gave her the wrong tea.
我想大概是我拿错杯子了
Mommy!
妈咪!
Mommy?
妈咪?
I told you. Ogres don't live happily ever after.
我说过  公主遇上妖怪 不会有好下场的!
Oh, Dad!
父王...
Harold
哈咯...
-  Is he...? - Yup.
- 这... - 对...
He croaked.
他挂了...
Harold?
哈洛?
Dad?
父王?
I'd hoped you'd never see me like this.
我多不希望你看到我的真面目
-  And he gave you a hard time! - Donkey!
- 天哪! 他比你还丑耶! - 驴子!
No, no, he's right. I'm sorry.
不  不  不  他说的没错
To both of you.I only wanted what was best for Fiona.
我对不起你们俩个 我一直希望费欧娜能够幸福
But I can see now...she already has it.
我现在看得出来... 她真的很幸福
Shrek, Fiona...
史瑞克  费欧娜...
Will you accept an old frog's apologies...
你们愿意接受 一只老青蛙的道歉...
and my blessing?
还有祝福吗?
Harold?
哈洛...
I'm sorry, Lillian.I just wish I could be the man you deserve.
对不起  莉雅  我希望我能成为值得你爱的男人
You're more that man today than you ever were...
你本来就是全世界 最值得我爱的男人...
warts and all.
永远都不会变
Boss! The Happily Ever After Potion!
老大! 药效时间快到了...
Midnight!
午夜了...
Fiona. Is this what you want?
费欧娜  你希望我们变成这样吗?
- To be this way forever?- What?
- 一辈子都这样? - 什么?
Because if you kiss me now...we can stay like this.
只要你现在吻我 我们一辈子都变成这样
You'd do that... For me?
你是为了我... 才改变的?
Yes.
是啊
I want what any princess wants.To live happily ever after...
我要每个公主都希望的结局 从此幸福快乐地...
with the ogre I married.
...跟妖怪在一起
Whatever happens, I must not cry!
我要坚强 我不可以哭!
You cannot make me cry!
你不能害我哭...
No. No, no. Aaah! Ow.
不要  不要  不要...
Hey. You still look like a noble steed to me.
你在我心目中 永远是一匹骏马!
Now, where were we?
对了  我们刚刚到哪了?
Oh. I remember.
我想起来了...
Hey! Isn't we supposed to be having a fiesta?
我们不是说好了 ...要开舞会吗?
Uno, dos, quatro,
一、二、三...
hit it!
来噢!
Puss and Donkey, y'all...
要唱歌了哦...
∮ She's into superstitions ∮
∮ 她痴于迷信 ∮
∮ Black cats and voodoo dolls ∮
∮ 黑猫跟巫毒降蛊 ∮
-  Sing it, Puss! -  ∮ I feel a premonition ∮
- 换你唱  猫咪!! - ∮ 我有种预感 ∮
∮ That girl's gonna make me fall ∮
∮ 她将会毁了我 ∮
Here we go!
不赖哦!
∮ She's into new sensations ∮
∮ 她喜欢有新鲜感 ∮
∮ New kicks in the candlelight ∮
∮ 烛光里的新舞姿 ∮
∮ She's got a new addiction ∮
∮ 不时变换新嗜好 ∮
∮ For every day and night ∮
∮ 每天每夜 ∮
∮ She'll make you take your clothes off ∮
∮ 她令你衣衫尽褪... ∮
∮ And go dancing in the rain ∮
∮ 在雨中漫舞 ∮
∮ She'll make you live her crazy life ∮
∮ 她令你过着她那样的疯狂生活 ∮
∮ But she'll take away your pain ∮
∮ 但她会带走你的痛苦 ∮
∮ Like a bullet to your brain ∮
∮ 像颗子弹射入你脑中 ∮
∮ Upside inside out ∮
∮ 上下内外颠覆 ∮
∮ Living la vida loca ∮
∮ 她过著疯狂的日子 ∮
Hey gorgeous!
嘿 帅哥!
∮ Living la vida loca ∮
∮ 过著疯狂的日子 ∮
∮ Her lips are devil red ∮
∮ 她恶魔般火红的嘴唇 ∮
∮ And her skin's the color of mocha ∮
∮ 古铜色般的肌肤 ∮
∮ She will wear you out ∮
∮ 她会把你累垮 ∮
∮ Living la vida loc. Oh! She livin' it loca! ∮
∮ 过著疯狂的日子 噢! 她过著疯狂的日子! ∮
∮ Living la vida loca ∮
∮ 过著疯狂的日子 ∮
- Say it one more time now! - ∮ Living the vida loca ∮
- 再一遍! - ∮ 过著疯狂的日子 ∮
Hey, Donkey, that's Spanish!
驴子 你唱的是西班牙文耶!
∮ She'll push and pull you down ∮
∮ 玩弄你于股掌间 ∮
∮ Living la vida loca ∮
∮ 过著疯狂的日子 ∮
∮ She will wear you out ∮
∮ 她将令你筋疲力尽 ∮
∮ Living la vida loca ∮
∮ 过著疯狂的日子 ∮
∮ She'll push and pull you down ∮
∮ 玩弄你于股掌间 ∮
∮ Living the vida loca ∮
∮ 过著疯狂的日子 ∮
∮ Her lips are devil red ∮
∮ 她恶魔般火红的嘴唇 ∮
∮ And her skin 's the color of mocha ∮
∮ 古铜色般的肌肤 ∮
∮ She will wear you out ∮
∮ 她将令你筋疲力尽 ∮
∮ Living la vida loca ∮
∮ 过著疯狂的日子 ∮
∮ OH...balaso... ∮
∮ 独自一人 ∮
∮ All by myself ∮
∮ 不再有你... ∮
∮ OH...balaso... ∮
∮ 独自一人 ∮
∮ All by myself anymore... ∮
∮ 从今后... ∮
Amigo, we are off to the Kit-Kat Club.
我们要去猫咪俱乐部
Come on, join us.
来啊  一块来啊
Thanks, compadre. I'm... I'm not in the mood.
谢了  兄弟 我心情很不好
We will cheer you up! Find you a nice burro!
我会让你开心的! 帮你找个...漂亮的小马子!
Hey, baby!
嘿 宝贝!
Hey, that's my girl! Yeah! All right!
嘿 是我马子! OH! 帅哦!
Baby, where you been?
宝贝 你去哪里啦?
I'm sorry, too.
我也对不起...
I should've stayed. But Shrek had this thing he had to do.
我应该陪你的 可是史瑞克有很重要的事
What? Say it one more time.
什么? 你再说一次
What you talking about? Are you serious?
真是? 你不要开玩笑了
Papa!
爸爸!
Look at our little mutant babies!
看看我们的小宝贝!
I got to get a job.
我得开始赚钱养家了